Hey Friends, Welcome to my YouTube channel
Easy Solution Motor Sports.  Today I have again
brought an informative video for you
that if Bajaj Chetak meets with an accident and
you have to make an insurance claim, then how do you make the
insurance claim?  What is the
process, how much is the charge,
which parts are covered, which
parts are not covered, I am going to give all the details
in this video.  So if you have
not subscribed to my channel yet, then please
subscribe to my YouTube channel and if
you find this video informative, then please
share it with your friends because this
video will be helpful to them too.  Now if I
talk about the process, you can check it out.
This is Bajaj Chetak.  She had fallen from the side.
Because of that it has got damaged.  From the front and from the
back.  You can check out.  The damage is done from the front
downwards in this manner.
So all this damage is covered in insurance.
Now which company's
insurance comes?  So mostly Bajaj
Insurance and God Digit insurance are
available.  I will show you the other scooter also.
You can check out.  This was an accident from the front.  There have been
more
accidents and more
problems in this.  You can check out.   There is
more damage on the bottom and the trunk side.  The chassis is also
its band.  So first of all if I
talk about the insurance company then it was Bajaj
Insurance and earlier it was Bajaj Insurance in cashless.
Now Go Digit has also come,
so Go Digit and Bajaj Insurance are
cashless.  If it is another company then it may be
non-cashless.  So you have to make the
payment first.  After that you will be reamed.
What is the process now?  So whenever such an
accident happens, you have to
take the scooter to the service centre and
give the customer's Aadhar card, PAN card, RC book, driving license and insurance copy to the service station.  After that, it is the job of the service engineer
that when this claim form comes, he will take
your signature on the claim form.  The claim
form will be filled and the accident claim
form contains all the details of the accident
like when it happened, how it happened, in what
manner it happened, all these details are filled out in it
and after that the claim intention is done.
This is a one day process.  The
surveyor comes when the claim is intimated.
Maximum surveyor comes in a day or two
and he takes photos of the scooter and
checks out how the accident happened.
So if he feels that the accident
is genuine and all the broken parts are
due to the accident, then he
passes the claim.  It takes about
a day or two for the claim to be approved and then the
work starts.  So when you
keep it at the service center, it will start working in 2 or 3 days.
Now which parts are covered
and which are not, then majorly all the
parts are covered.  There is no such thing
that this part is not covered.  But
if the surveyor feels that it is
not due to an accident, then he does not cover those parts, then
he will have to pay a separate
charge.  Otherwise all the parts are covered.
And what parts are missing
?  So only the tyres that come with the scooter are
not covered.  Now
how much total time does it take?  So, mostly if all the
parts are available in the service station
then you get your scooter within 10 days.  It does
n't take much more time than that.
Now if I talk about the charges, if you
talk about the file charge then the file charge is like ₹350.  In that case the
scooter has zero dep
insurance.  Now if I talk about parts,
then there is a
difference of around ₹100 to ₹200.
Because the parts that are not installed have
not been damaged in the accident.  If the surveyor feels like this then
I will give an example that your
mirror was broken earlier.  I had fallen earlier then.
Now you have made a claim and the surveyor
feels that the mirror was not broken in your accident.  The
liver was not broken in the accident.  It was
broken before.  If the
scooter has fallen in this manner then this lever cannot
break.  So he can reject those parts.
So the two mirrors cost ₹12000.
So if you want to get it installed then
you will have to pay ₹1200 separately.  So whenever there are
parts that are not covered in the insurance, the
engineer installs them only after asking you whether you want to
install those parts or not.  If you
ask him to put it in, then you will have to
pay extra for it, like if it is for the lever, if it is for the mirror then it will cost Rs
1200, so you will have to pay that charge separately.
Otherwise, there is no charge.
All the details are kept in this manner.
You do not have to pay any separate charges.  This is how the
entire insurance process takes place.
I hope you found this video helpful.
So please share this video.  Thank
you.